EVGENY ARBATOV

Full Stack Engineer

📞 +6597368514 🛛 @ arbatovevgeny@gmail.com 📝 linkedin.com/in/evgeniyarbatov Singapore

SUMMARY

Engineer with over 10 years of experience in building products and backends. Designed integrations between Meta and mobile carriers in APAC. Have hands-on experience with software engineering, data analysis and project management. Writing code in JavaScript, Golang and Python. Have good communication and problem solving skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staff Business Engineer

Meta

= 03/2023 - 09/2023 Singapore

- Created custom partner solutions and resolved technical blockers
- Defined roadmap for developing new product features
- Worked on user growth and payments optimization
- Ran A/B tests to evaluate impact of code changes

Senior Partner Engineer

Meta

= 06/2019 - 03/2023 Singapore

- Optimized carrier integrations and developed new products
- Launched new payment methods and integrations with mobile carriers
- Performed data deep dives to tune product performance
- Created apps to promote digital literacy and simplify user onboarding
- Developed tooling to monitor state of network configurations

Partner Engineer

Facebook

- Enabled new growth opportunities in partnership with carriers by launching free Facebook campaigns and building APIs for payments
- Made network and configuration changes to enable the service
- Designed API integrations for data plan recommendation engines

Software Engineer

Pryte

= 02/2014 - 06/2014

Finland

- Developed a way for mobile carriers to offer data plans for apps
- Created frontend of mobile carrier portal
- Took part in oncall rotations

Software Engineer

Blaast

= 05/2013 - 01/2014

Finland

- Made apps for feature phones to make online services accessible
- Built API integrations with mobile carriers
- Developed tooling to deploy code to production

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences

Specialized in computer networks and information security

SKILLS

PHP Python **JavaScript** SQL **AWS** ReactJS Golang Data Engineering Scripting NodeJS

ACHIEVEMENTS

Internet.org launches

Led technical discussions and built integrations with mobile carriers to bring new users online and create monetization opportunities.

Digital literacy app

Created backend of Android app for promoting digital literacy in partnership with GSMA.

WhatsApp chatbot

Developed backend of WhatsApp chatbot for mobile carrier retailers.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -Associate

Jan 2024

CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Feb 2024

STRENGTHS

Data analysis

Analyzed data on the performance of live integrations to find growth opportunities.

Communication skills

Rolled out new products and investigated production issues. Acted as the first point of contact between Meta and mobile carriers.

Mentoring

Volunteered with Generation Singapore to mentor people who transition to a career in IT.